In India they were all waiting for the monsoons
在印度 他们都在等待雨季到来
and they are so worried
而且很担心
because the rain did not come.
因为雨一直没来
So, I was giving bandhan to the rain and it came here
所以 我刚才正在班丹下雨 它来到了这里
And now also they have  told,
现在他们也在电视上说了
But first in Italy!
但首先下在意大利
I was told that in Italy you needed rain very much
我听说意大利也非常需要下雨
and the first rain you had,
几天前是第一场雨
Because all the understanding
因为我们的农民
of the problems of our farmers is there.
对问题的理解就在那里
And the rain, you see, is so kind
你知道 雨是如此的善解人意
that it works at the right time.
它在准确的时间工作
I am surprised
我对这雨如此快速的反馈 和顺从感到惊喜
Today is a great day, for all of us,  because
今天对我们所有人来说 都是很好的一天
and remembering all the great Gurus
并记住所有来到这个世界上 伟大的导师们
So many of them were [there].
他们中的很多人都来过
And they tried their level best
尽他们最大的努力
to explain to humanity what is spirituality.
向人类解释什么是灵性
But it’s such a disparity that people never understood
但是人们理解偏差
that spirituality is the most important thing we need.
不理解灵性是我们所需要的 最重要的事情
That we have to be one with the Divine Power.
我们必须与上天的力量合而为一
All their endeavours have been in the wrong direction.
他们所有的努力都走向了错误的方向
First of course they were very intelligent, more than animals,
首先当然他们非常聪明 远高于动物
and started seeking, not the truth,
并开始寻求 不是真理
but some sort of a self
而是某种自我解脱
self-progress.
自我进步
And in that they lost that they have to first seek spirituality,
因为他们迷失了 他们必须首先寻求灵性
which is the most important thing.
这是最重要的事情
But, we had two types of journeys:
但是 我们有两种类型的旅程
one is through the left side or another through the right side.
一个是通过左脉 另一个是通过右脉
In India, I don’t know why,
在印度 我不知道为什么
we had lots of people who went into the jungles and became saints
我们有很多人进入丛林而成为圣人
but they were doing right side tapasya.
但他们做的是右脉的苦行
That is, going into the five elements
也就是说 他们一个个进入五大元素
Of course there is truth in it, no doubt.
毫无疑问 当然这里面有真相
You have seen how a candle
你看过一支蜡烛怎样
how a candle tells you as to what is your position inside:
蜡烛怎样告诉你内在的状况
if you are possessed or if you are not,
如果你被附身或没被附身
a candle can tell you – can you imagine?
蜡烛可以告诉你 你能想象吗
Candle is so much knowledgable.
蜡烛是如此有学问
Supposing you have a heart, heart trouble –
假设你有心脏病
the candle will show.
蜡烛会显示出来
And if you treat yourself with a candle, you can cure yourself.
如果你治疗自己 你可以治愈自己
So, it is so sensitive
所以 它是如此敏感
not that it can cure, but also so competent,
不但可以治愈 而且也很有能力
not that it shows you that you are sick and you have problems
它不但可以告诉你你生病了 你有问题
but that it is competent to cure you.
而且有能力治愈你
Thats why, in India, Agni was worshipped,
这就是为什么在印度 火神被崇拜
this  light was worshipped,
光元素被崇拜
the fire was worshipped, that was worshipped first.
火被崇拜 这些首先被崇拜
They must have discovered that the fire knows everything,
他们一定发现火知道一切
so the inner, inner awareness of all these elements,
所以所有元素的内在知觉
they knew about it and thats why they worshipped those elements.
他们知道这一点 这就是为什么他们崇拜这些元素
So before the Puja they used to call all the Deities who belonged
因此 在普祭之前他们会召唤 所有属于这些元素的神祇
But that turned out to be right sided movement.
但人们把它弄成右脉的活动
Without the left side right side is very dangerous.
没有左脉 只有右脉是非常危险的
If you don’t have right side of course
如果你没有右脉
development of your left side.
发展你的左脉
That is what, to begin with, we had in Sahaja Yoga.
这就是我们在霎哈嘉瑜伽中 首先开始的事情
Left side is compassion, is love, universal feeling,
左脉是慈悲 是爱 是普遍的感觉
which are described you know it, in the Devi Mahatmyam,
这在《女神颂》中被描述过 你知道的
that the Goddess resides within you as so many things.
女神以许多形相存在于你之内
She resides within you as shraddha.
祂以信心 睡眠
as, She resides in you as sleep,
幻象 迷惑的形相
She resides in you as illusion, bhranti.
存在于你之内
All kinds of things are there on the left-hand side,
在左脉 祂以各种各样的形相存在
which are already described.
这已经描述过了
And when I told you about Sahaja Yoga,
当我向你们讲述霎哈嘉瑜伽的时候
I wanted to make your left side very strong.
我想让你们的左脉变得强壮
Those who, people who, took to right side
那些被带到右脉的人
became very aggressive people, and they had mastered
变得非常有侵略性 他们已经掌握了
the essence of these five elements, that’s alright. But
这五大元素的本质 没关系
so much so that they used to curse people, curse them.
甚至他们过去常常诅咒别人 诅咒他们
They used to say things which were not kind;
他们经常说不友善的事
and they didn’t believe in the universality.
他们不相信整体存有
It was such a dangerous thing that they took.
这是非常危险的事情 以致于他们被带到右脉
In Indian shastras you can see many incidents
在印度典籍中 你可以看到许多人们
where people gave a curse, sharp, very common.
诅咒别人 说话尖锐的事件 非常普遍
All these gurus used to curse a person,
所有这些导师过去常常诅咒别人
because they had no compassion, no love, nothing but they had powers
因为他们没有慈悲心 没有爱心 什么也没有只有右脉的力量
that those people who have right side,
那些右脉的人
who go only on the right side without the bhakti,
只处在右脉 没有虔敬的人
without the blessings of the Divine,
没有上天的祝福
can become rakshasas actually,
实际上会成为罗刹魔
can become a great danger for humanity.
会成为人类巨大的危险
This is a very serious thing:
这是一个非常严重的事情
through your intelligence, through your thinking power,
通过你的智商 通过你的思维能力
your ego can go to any limit
你的自我可以达到任何极限
and create problems within you.
并在你内在制造问题
Now the ultimate of this problem is,
现在这个问题的最终结果是
we have seen is, are many diseases,
我们已经看到 有很多疾病
which are absolutely incurable.
是绝对无法治愈的
Even some people, right-sided, some people,
甚至有些右脉的人
can get a kind of a cancer called blood cancer.
会得一种叫做血癌的癌症
And this blood cancer, now we have cured it,
而这种血癌 现在我们能治好了
but even if it is cured you can go back
但即使它被治愈 你也可能回到
to that kind of aggressiveness
那种侵略性
thinking that you are very right.
以为你是非常正确的
Such people always try to find faults with others,
这样的人总是试图找别人的错
that such and such person is not good, he’s doing harm,
这样的人 那样的人不好 他在伤害别人
or any way they can find faults with others, not with themselves.
或者无论如何他们都能找到 他人的错误 而不是自己的错误
Their attention is outside, not on themselves.
他们的注意力总是在外面 而不是在他们自己身上
They never see what’s wrong with them,
他们从来看不到自己有什么问题
but they always see what’s wrong with others.
但他们总能看出别人的问题
By doing that, you see, they are climbing the ladder
以这样的方式 你们知道 他们正在爬上一个可怕的
of a horrible right side, which can give you horrible diseases.
右脉的梯子 那会给你带来可怕的疾病
As I’ve told you, first is the blood cancer.
正如我告诉过你们的 首先就是血癌
If you get rid of the blood cancer then
如果你摆脱了血癌
you can get into another problems. Nowadays there’s a very famous
你可能会陷入另外的问题
This is also the side of the right side;
这也是右脉的问题
because if you don’t have that bhakti, that humility,
因为如果你没有那种虔敬 谦卑
that blessings of the Goddess,
没有女神的祝福
you can develop all such horrible diseases
你会得所有这些可怕的疾病
which are not only fatal,
这些疾病不仅是致命的
but also very injurious to others.
也是非常伤人的
So by being right-sided you do not progress.
所以处于右脉 你不会进步
You can become a big ascetic, they call it,
你可以成为一个别人口中的 大苦行僧
who can curse others,
能诅咒别人
who can put them into troubles,
能让别人陷入困境
think that that is a great power – it is not!
认为那是一种强大的力量 并非如此
It is not at all.
完全不是这样
Because, though you are not suppressed
因为 虽然你没有被
by other powers, negative powers,
其他负面力量压制
but your own power takes your life.
但是你自己的力量夺走了你的生命
So Kundalini, when it is arisen,
所以昆达利尼 当它升起时
the best thing is to go to the left side,
最好的事情是走到左脉
not criticising others, not talking ill of others,
不批评别人 不说别人的坏话
but seeing within you, what’s wrong.
但是看看你的内在 有什么问题
Find out what is the matter with you.
找出你的问题
First it starts with self-importance,
首先 它始于妄自尊大
that “I am a very important person,”
我是一个非常重要的人
and with this self-importance you go on
因为这种妄自尊大
But because of your right-side movement,
但是由于你的右脉活动
you can become very successful.
你可以变得非常成功
Hitler was the climax of that.
希特勒就是这样的极端
And that’s how people start taking to very, very cruel things.
随后人们开始做 非常非常残酷的事情
Nowadays, I think that some people are
如今 我认为有些人
ruling  everywhere with their right side.
正用他们的右脉统治各处
We do not have people who are using their left side.
我们没有人使用他们的左脉
And whenever they use their left side they are called as saints.
每当他们使用他们左脉时 他们被称为圣人
Now you all have the powers of the left side.
现在你们都拥有左脉的力量
Some of you do have little bit right side also, doesn’t matter.
你们当中有些人也有一点点偏右 没关系
Now I would say that you have achieved
现在我想说你已经取得了
your left side mastery:
左脉的成就
Kundalini awakening is there, you are one with the Divine.
昆达里尼已经唤醒 你和上天的力量合一
Now you can come to the right side and know about right side,
现在你可以来到右脉 了解右脉
and try to express your right side.
并尝试表达你的右脉
You can express it not by dominating others but dominating yourself.
你可以表达它 不是通过控制别人而是通过控制自己
By self-examination.
通过自省
By understanding what’s wrong with you. Why do you behave like that?
通过了解你自己的缺点 你为什么这么做
Why do you trouble others? Why do you overpower others?
你为什么要麻烦他人 你为什么压倒他人
Such people will always, I have seen, organise
我见过这样的人 他们组织事情
and arrange, and do this and do that.
安排事情 做这做那
Instead of organising themselves they’ll organise others.
他们不管理自己 却管理他人
These things complicate.
把事情变得复杂
But if you have love and if you have bhakti,
但如果你有爱 如果你有虔诚奉献
you can very, very easily
你可以非常容易
dominate  others in a very different manner.
以非常不同的方式主导其他人
It is not that you dominate by cruelty,
不是通过残忍管制
by oppression, but you dominate with your love.
不是通过压迫 而是你通过爱来主导
And you don’t want to dominate,
你不想宰制
but easily people get very much succumbed
但人们很容易就顺服于
to love and to magnanimity, to generosity.
爱 宽容和慷慨
So all these qualities you must first develop within yourself:
因此 你首先必须在自己内在 发展所有这些品质
is the left-side problem, that – you should be very peaceful,
这是左脉的问题 你应该很平和
you should give love to others, you should be generous,
你应该关爱别人 你应该慷慨
you should be kind, and see how much it pays.
你应该友善 看看它能花多少钱
I’ve seen some people who are extremely rude,
我见过一些极其粗鲁的人
they can be rude to anyone, that’s their nature,
他们对任何人都很粗鲁 这是他们的本性
which they should overcome with the left side.
他们应该用左脉来克服这些
Rudeness is not the sign of a saint.
粗鲁并不是圣人的标志
A saint is extremely peaceful,
圣人极其平和
and never gets rude with others.
从不会对别人粗鲁
So the introspection should work first of all,
因此首先应该内省
“Where are we wrong? What wrong things we are doing?
我们哪里错了 我们做了什么错事
What is our style?”
我们的风格是什么
Once you discover that your style is already left-side,
一旦你发现你的风格 已经有左脉的力量了
then you should take to right side
你就可以来到右脉
and possess the power of right side.
并拥有右脉的力量
What are the powers of right side now
现在右边的力量是什么
which are achieved through the left-side perfection?
哪些是通过完善左脉可以达成的
We have some very great Gurus on this line.
我们在这里有一些非常伟大的导师
One of them was Raja Janaka.
其中一个是拉贾.加纳克
He was a ruler of a country,
他是一个国家的统治者
and a very well-known ruler and everything; but still, still,
一个非常出名的统治者 但仍然
though He was so generous and good and everything,
他是如此慷慨 善良
but at the same time He was a great monarch,
同时 他是一位伟大的君主
great king of those days,
当时伟大的国王
very much known for His impartiality,  for His statesmanship
因其公正而闻名 因为他的政治才能
and all kinds of beautiful things He did for His
以及他为国家所做的各种好事而出名
He could not get disturbed with anything.
他不会被任何事情打扰
And people never understood
人们不理解
why the greatest of greatest saints used to bow to Him.
为什么最伟大的圣人 都常常向他鞠躬行礼
What was so great? Though He was a king, He was living so lavishly
为什么呢 尽管他是国王 生活奢华
and He had so many of ornaments and
尽管他有很多饰物
also conveyances and all that;
和很多交通工具和所有这些
because nothing was above Him,
但因为没有什么凌驾于他
He was so detached with everything.
他不执着于这一切
He had everything, but He was so detached.
他拥有一切 但他如此不执着
That’s a very good example of a person
这是一个掌握左脉力量的典范
Like that we had many people later on also,
我们后来也有很多人像这样
one after another, who were extremely, extremely rich,
一个接一个 他们极其富有
but inside they were
但他们的内在
Nothing disturbed them, nothing made them feel greater or happier.
没有什么能打扰他们 没有什么让他们感到更伟大或更快乐
No position, no power was to them great.
没有什么名 利对他们来说是巨大的
This is a complete emancipation of human beings,
你们是获得自觉的灵
that you are realised soul.
这是人类的彻底解脱
You should be fully equipped with compassion love and understanding.
你们应该充满慈悲 爱和谅解
But at the same time, it should be expressed in the right way.
但与此同时 它应该以正确的方式表达
For example, we can say Christ, He’s another example.
例如 我们可以说基督 祂是另一个例子
Though He was an Incarnation, still
虽然祂是一个降世神祇
the amount of forgiveness and love He has for people is tremendous.
但祂依然对人们有巨大的宽恕和爱
But at the same time,
但与此同时
He used to go on the mountains and preach about spirituality.
祂过去常常去山上宣讲灵性
Those were not very safe times,
在那个时代不是很安全
because people didn’t like anybody talking like that.
因为人们不喜欢任何人那样说
They hated Him because He talked about God.
他们恨祂 因为祂谈到了上帝
And what they did to Him you know very well.
他们对祂所做的事情 你们很清楚
Doesn’t matter.
没关系
Though they crucified Him, still
虽然他们把祂钉死在十字架上
Reason is, He was, He was no doubt an Incarnation,
原因是 毫无疑问祂是一个降世神祇
but still He went all out to give His achievements or
但祂仍然全力以赴地把祂的成就
He went all over the places, He had no facilities,
祂走遍了各个地方 没有任何工具
but still He went out to many people
但祂还是见了很多人
and tried to save them.
并试图拯救他们
This was the right-side movement.
这是右脉的活动
That means Sahaja Yogis can also become right-sided,but like Christ.
这意味着霎哈嘉瑜伽士 也可以变得右脉 但要像基督一样
Otherwise if they are right-sided
否则 如果他们是右脉的
they’ll organise, they’ll do all kinds of things,
他们会组织 他们会做各种各样的事情
That’s why I want you to avoid the right side.
这就是为什么我要你们避免右脉
But once you are fully a left-sided master of Sahaja Yoga,
但是 一旦你完全掌握 霎哈嘉瑜伽的左脉力量
then it’s very, very much needed
接着必须要成为
to be a complete personality of spirituality,
一个整合的灵性人格
that you should take to right-side movement.
你应该有右脉的行动
And what is the right-side movement is the collectivity.
右脉的行动就是集体性
Should not be satisfied with what you have got.
不应该满足于你们所拥有的
It’s very easy
人们很容易感觉
to feel, “Oh, now we have got realisation, now what is there?
哦 现在我们已经得到自觉 还有什么呢
We are on top of the world!” That’s not so.
我们处于世界巅峰 并非如此
You have to go out, talk to people.
你们必须走出去 告知人们
They will insult you, they’ll trouble you,
他们会侮辱你 会麻烦你
But you are already a person, already a realised soul.
但你已经是另外一种人 一个已经得到自觉的灵
You can listen to them, what they are saying;
你可以倾听他们 听他们在说什么
you will not ask for anything, but you’d like to do good to them.
你不要求任何东西 你只是想对他们好
This is also a compassion,
这也是一种慈悲心
that you don’t want to keep your realisation to yourself,
你不想把自觉留给自己
but you want to do it
而是想分享给别人
for others also so that they also get realisation,
让他们也得到自觉
it’s very important. If you do not feel that way,
这很重要 如果你没有那样的感受
the pity for people who haven’t got realisation,
不同情那些还没得到自觉的人
think of the times you were not realised.
想想你还没得到自觉的时候
These people are also not realised and they are having a bad time,
那些没得到自觉的人 正在经历艰难时刻
they can be in for any trouble.
他们会有麻烦的
So now, it’s not that if you have got realisation
所以现在 不是如果你们得到了自觉
you settle down with it – no, that’s not the way;
就自己安顿下来 不是这样
but you should go all out to see
你们都应该走出去
that you give realisation to others, and save them.
给别人带自觉 去拯救他们
You all have got realisation not for your sake,
你们都得到了自觉 不是只为了自己
it’s not limited for you, but it is meant for others,
局限于自己 也是为了他人
that you have to give it to others.
带给他人自觉
And as soon as you’ll start giving it to others you’ll be amazed,
一旦你们开始给别人自觉 你们会惊喜
so many qualities in you will come up;
你内在那么多美好的品质开始显现
because when you see others, you find
因为当你们看别人
what do they need, what you have to give,  how you have to give.
他们需要什么 你们必须给予什么 必须怎么给予
You can become anything, you can become a poet,
你们可以成为任何人 可以成为诗人
in case you face others.
你们可以成为任何人
Then it comes as a reaction within you, all these qualities develop,
然后作为一种回应 所有这些品质在你之内开始发展
and you become a very good, I should say, artist.
你成为一个很好的 我应该说 艺术家
This is only possible if you meet other people
只有当你们面见他人
and talk to them about Sahaja Yoga,
跟他们谈霎哈嘉瑜伽
and tell them about your Self-realisation.
跟他们谈你的自觉的时候 这才可能发生
I know there will be problems, I know. That is true.
我知道会有问题 我知道 这是真的
There will be people who will oppose you, say
会有人反对你们
But that’s the thing you should achieve,
但那是你们应该达成的事情
is to meet people, talk to them
面见他人 与他们交谈
and start telling them about Self-realisation you have to save them.
并开始告诉他们自觉 你们必须拯救他们
That’s important.
这很重要
But first of all you should know that you should have no right-sided
但首先你们应该知道 你们应该没有右脉的问题
A person who is spiritual is supposed
一个属灵的人
or accepted to be a very humble person.
是人们认为或公认 是一个非常谦卑的人
Of course because he is humble, people will take advantage of him,
当然因为他很谦卑 人们会利用他
say all kinds of things, it’s alright, is a part of the game.
说各种各样的话 没关系 这是游戏的一部分
But, he doesn’t mind, he doesn’t mind anything.
但是他不介意 他不介意任何事
Anything that comes his way, he doesn’t mind.
无论他遇到任何事 他都不介意
But what is the main thing is that he has compassion.
但最主要的是他有慈悲心
His compassion that he had before from the left side is now expanded
他之前来自左脉的慈悲心开始扩展
and he wants to save the people.
他想要拯救人们
People don’t have food, is alright, it’s a big complication;
人们没有食物 好吧 这是个难题
if people are starving is another;
如果人们挨饿是另一种情况
but if they do not get spirituality,
但如果他们得不到灵性
what’s the use of their human life,
那成为人又有什么用
why did they evolve to this state?
为什么他们进化到这个状态
They are evolved from animal state,
他们是从动物的状态
from the worst possible to a human state.
从最糟糕的条件进化到人类的状态
And now if they do not get their realisation,
现在 如果他们得不到自觉
that means this is worse than starving,
这意味着这比饥饿更糟
worse than all kinds of poverty,
比各种贫困更糟
worse than all kinds of diseases and troubles.
比各种疾病和麻烦更糟
So why not try to give them realisation?
那么为什么不尝试给他们自觉呢
Why not see that you give them realisation?
为什么看不到你们给他们自觉
But first and foremost thing, as I said,
但首要的 正如我所说
that in the left you should be very strong.
你们的左脉应该非常强大
You shouldn’t start doing it because you have got your realisation,
你们不应该因为自己得到了自觉
you can give realisation.
就开始带自觉
So you should not start doing it
应该等到你们的左脉加强以后
unless and until you have strengthened your left side.
才开始带自觉
Such a person is extremely humble,
这样的人极其谦卑
extremely straight, doesn’t grudge about anything,
极其坦率 对任何事情都不抱怨
doesn’t grumble about anything,
什么都不抱怨
and can adjust itself into any circumstance.
并可以适应任何情况
It is not attached to anything.
它不执着于任何东西
It’s an automatic detachment, it doesn’t have to detach.
这是一个自动的不执著 它不是被迫的
You may do anything for that person,
你可以为那个人做任何事
you may try to get anything for that person, it’s alright.
你可以尝试为那个人得到任何东西 没关系
That person will accept, no doubt,
毫无疑问 那个人会接受
but without any attachment to anything.
但没有任何执着
Such a detached person is the one who can work it out,
这样一个不执著的人可以成就
all kinds of propagation of Sahaja Yoga.
霎哈嘉瑜伽的各种传播
Today that is the greatest need of the world,
今天这世界上最大的需求
that we have to have more Sahaja Yogis.
是我们必须有更多的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Now, people are so shy to do that,
现在有些人会很害羞这样做
it’s very surprising.
这非常令人惊讶
But I have seen people who don’t have any truth,
但我看到有些人 他们没有任何真理
who have all kinds of bad gurus,
跟过各种坏导师
get after others, try to spread their false ideas.
却到处找人试图传播他们错误的想法
But Sahaja Yogis, why should they feel,
但霎哈嘉瑜伽士
why should they feel shy, I don’t understand.
他们为什么觉得害羞 我不明白
So, talk about this to everyone, bring them to Sahaja Yoga.
所以 向每个人谈论这个 把他们带到霎哈嘉瑜伽来
Is a very important day, because as a Guru puja,
今天是非常重要的一天 因为作为一个导师普祭
they say that a guru cannot give anything to you.
他们说导师不能给你们什么东西
But I can give you the advice,
但我可以给你们建议
and the advice that you enlarge your heart,
建议你们扩展你们的心
you become humble, and try to spread Sahaja Yoga
变得谦卑 并尝试谦卑地传播霎哈嘉瑜伽
That is extremely important.
这极其重要
If you can do that, then you’ll do full justice
如果你们能做到这一点 那这一生
Without that you cannot achieve, you cannot achieve,
如果做不到这样 你们无法实现
the strength of spirituality.
你们无法实现 属灵的力量
For that you haveto understand that it’s very, very important
为此你们必须明白 这是非常非常重要的
that you should give Sahaja Yoga a full chance,through your wisdom.
你们应该通过你们的智慧 给霎哈嘉瑜伽一个完全的机会
What I receive [is] mostly the letters are
我收到的大多数信件
that person is doing like that. Forget it!
这个人那样做 算了吧
All such persons are not important for Sahaja Yoga.
所有这些人对霎哈嘉瑜伽都不重要
But if you start on proper lines you will be amazed,
但如果你开始正确的线路 你会感到惊讶
you’ll meet so many people who want peace of mind,
你会遇到那么多想要头脑平和的人
peace of heart and a complete oneness with the Divine.
想要内心平和 想要和上天完全合一的人
They may not accept, they may not say,
他们可能不会接受 他们可能不会说
they might have gone to the wrong people also, possibly.
他们可能也会曾经跟随错的人
But despite everything,
但尽管如此
they would like to have a real spiritual peace within themselves.
他们希望在自己内在 拥有真正的灵性平和
Is a very common desire nowadays among people,
现在这是人们非常普遍的愿望
but to approach that and to reach that,
但要接近并达到目标
you have to take to a life of a very simple personality.
你必须过上一种 有非常简单人格的生活
You see, if you are so much interested in money,
你看 如果你对钱很感兴趣
or if you are so much interested in your so-called powers
或者如果你对你所谓的权力 或你的野心感兴趣
But if you are interested in your compassion
但如果你对你的慈悲心
and understanding about today’s world,
和理解今天的世界感兴趣
how it is in a turmoil: why?
它是如何陷入混乱的 为什么
Because of the human beings being in the wrong.
因为人类自己处于错误之中
What we have to do is to pass them the knowledge of the Divine.
我们要做的 就是传递给他们上天的知识
That should be your desire,
这应该是你的愿望
and that is what you’ll feel very much comfortable with.
这会让你感到非常舒服
All other desires, all other wants are,
所有其他的欲望 所有其他的愿望
as you say, it’s very transitory.
正如你所说 都是非常短暂的
One desire is to spread Sahaja Yoga,
传播霎哈嘉瑜伽的愿望
is so beautiful that you go on working on it,
是如此美丽 以至于你持续致力于此
and every time you do that,
每次你这样做
you will be so joyous and happy,
你会如此喜悦和幸福
you’ll have no problems of any kind.
你不会有任何问题
That’s the sign of greatness of Sahaja Yoga,
这是霎哈嘉瑜伽伟大的标志
and I want you all to become like that.
我希望你们都成为那样
As today’s day is great, because
今天的日子很伟大
and who tried to lead us.  What they did,
他们试着引导我们
all of them tried to spread the truth all over the world.
他们所做的一切 都尝试向全世界传播真理
They suffered a lot, they had problems, so many problems,
他们遭受了很多苦难 他们遇到问题 很多问题
but they worked very hard in every way to spread Sahaja Yoga
但他们非常努力地工作 以各种方式传播霎哈嘉瑜伽
and talk about God anddivinity.
并谈论上帝与神性
All that is what today you have to give Me,
综上 今天你们要给我一个承诺
you can tell them about Sahaja Yoga.
你要告诉他们霎哈嘉瑜伽
Not that it’s important but it’s absolutely
并不是说它很重要
immediate need of the world.
而是说这是世界迫切需要的
If you understand this point,
如果你明白这一点
that at this time, why are you in this world
你为什么在这个时候来到这个世界上
and what is the need of the world,
什么是这个世界的需要
you will immediately start feeling the responsibility.
你会立即开始感受到这个责任
Whether you are a man or a woman is not important.
你是男人还是女人并不重要
Go all out to preach, think,
全力以赴地去宣讲 思考
make people understand about Sahaja  Yoga
让人们了解霎哈嘉瑜伽
in every way that is possible,
以各种可能的方式
and I think, then, you will become complete as gurus.
如此一来 我想你才能完全成为一个导师
If Sahaja Yoga is just with you, you cannot be a guru.
如果霎哈嘉瑜伽只存在于你自身 你就不能成为一个导师
‘Guru’ also doesn’t mean that you go on preaching about Sahaja Yoga
导师 也不意味着 你一直讲述霎哈嘉瑜伽
talking about Sahaja Yoga, giving lectures about Sahaja Yoga, no!
谈论霎哈嘉瑜伽 讲授霎哈嘉瑜伽 不
It means the one who gives realisations to others.
它意味着给他人带自觉
How many people you give realisation is the thing,
关键的是你给多少人带去自觉
not to be counted,  but to be felt within like the ripples,
不要去数算 但要在内在感受
waves of the Ocean of Love in your heart.
像涟漪一样 你心中那爱的海洋的浪花
So beautiful it is to see that people get realisation
看到人们得到自觉
and are immersed in the joy of spirituality.
并融入到灵性的喜悦中 是多么美好啊
That’s what I want you to do. That’s why I am on this earth.
这就是我想要你们做的 这就是我来到这个世界上的原因
I had to suffer also quite a lot, doesn’t matter:
我不得不也遭受很多苦难 没关系
so-called sufferings, I was watching it just like a drama.
所谓的苦难 我都视作一场戏剧
So it’s ok.
所以没关系
As long as you do not pay much attention
只要你不太注意
to all these sufferings, what is so great?
只要你不太在意这些苦难 又有什么了不起的
Now you have seen yesterday a beautiful drama about Mohammad Sahib.
昨天你们已经看了那部 关于默罕默德的精彩戏剧
I always used to think,  and it was such pain, about Him,  that
我以前常想 对祂来说这是多么痛苦
why they are doing all wrong things? Now,
为什么人们要做这些错事
and have understood and made such a beautiful drama out of it.
理解祂并制作了如此美丽的戏剧
I don’t know how far we can propagate this,
我不知道我们可以传播多远
but it’s a fact that Mohammad Sahib Himself
但事实上默罕默德自己去世了
His son-in-law was finished.
他的女婿也去世了
And after that, by finishing them,
在他们去世后
they started another horrible thing called Sunnis.
出现了可怕的逊尼派教徒
Now, the Sunnah religion is not near the truth at all,
现在的逊尼派根本远离真理
it’s some sort of a very aggressive and a very cruel religion,
这是一种非常具有攻击性 和非常残忍的宗教
and that started spreading everywhere.
并开始在各地蔓延
In the real Islam religion of Mohammed Sahib was not there.
在真正的穆罕默德伊斯兰教中 残忍根本不存在
Those people who killed Him started becoming ‘Islamic’.
那些杀死他的人开始变成 伊斯兰教徒
So this is also a very wrong thing,
所以这也是一个非常错误的事情
was not just accepted,
不被接受
and somebody who killed Him is now accepted.
现在人们接受了一个杀死祂的人
It can happen in anything.
任何事情都可能发生
But the worst it has happened in is Islamic world,
但最糟糕的是发生在伊斯兰世界
which is very dangerous, and that’s we see
这是非常危险的 我们看到了
that, in the name of God, how many bad things they are doing.
他们以上帝之名 在做着多少坏事
So, try to understand
所以 试着去理解
that it is not the fate of Mohammad Sahib it has happened,
发生的这些事不是默罕默德的命运
it’s not the fate of reality it has happened,
也不是实相的命运
but it’s an eye-opener for all of us to see
但它让我们所有人都大开眼界
that the Truth is always challenged by untruth.
真理总是被假相所挑战
And we should stand by the Truth, whatever may happen.
无论发生什么 我们都应该坚持真理
And a day will come when people will realise
总有一天人们会意识到
that this was a wrong thing they were being,
他们一直以来是错的
all the time been following,
跟随着错误
and have been doing all kinds of nonsensical things.
且一直在做各种荒谬的事情
All this will work out I am sure, very soon,
所有这一切都会成就 我相信很快就会实现
if My desire is that powerful, I’m sure
如果我的愿望那么强大
May God bless you.
愿上帝保佑你